New York Coat and Suit Association. Records. 6036/021
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
New York Coat and Suit Association Records.
1910-1969
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
New York Coat and Suit Association
6036/021
7 cubic feet
7 linear ft.
Articles, reprints, pamphlets, correspondence, photographs.
This collection contains correspondence and memoranda, meeting materials, financial records, surveys, and bulletins of the New York Coat and Suit Association and related organizations.
5767601
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 07, 2011
EAD encoding:
Kathryn Dowgiewicz, January 10, 2013
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1900 by local union delegates representing about 2,000 members in cities in the northeastern United States, the ILGWU grew in geographical scope, membership size, political influence to become one of the most powerful forces in American organized labor by mid-century. Representing workers in the women's garment industry, the ILGWU worked to improve working and living conditions of its members through collective bargaining agreements, training programs, health care facilities, cooperative housing, educational opportunities, and other efforts. In 1995, the ILGWU merged with the Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers Union (ACTWU) to form the Union of Needletrades, Industrial and Textile Employees (UNITE).
Scope and Contents
The New York Coat and Suit Association was an organization comprised of coat and suit manufacturers in New York City. The majority of the records in the collection are during the tenure of Joseph Dubow, who was the executive director for many years. The collection contains material of local matters including tax, city government, insurance, unemployment, and commercial rent. Also included is material of national matters including documents on the cleaning instruction label that appears on garments, known as the "care" label, flammability regulations of fabric, numerous documents on the impact of imports in the textile industry, and records and correspondence regarding the Federal Trade Commission (FTC), in particular the Wool Products Labeling Act of 1939, advertising allowances, and fake fur labeling. A section of the collection consists of special notice fliers advertising meetings and events, general mass correspondence to members, and bulletins, all arranged according to year. Many surveys and studies of the coat and suit industry with statistics, trends and market data, buying behavior and opinions are present, as well as public relations material along with photographs for ad campaigns, one marketing fake fur to children and teens.
Much of the collection contains records from other organizations and associations, including bound meeting minute books from the Executive Committee of the Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers Protective Association from 1910-1917. There is correspondence and documents of the Apparel Industries Inter-Association Committee (comprised of apparel manufacturing associations, though originally formed by a few outerwear apparel associations) of which the New York Coat and Suit Association was a member.
A large component of the collection includes the records of the National Coat and Suit Industry Recovery Boards, the organization that was formed in 1935 with management and labor to continue the codes and standards set forth by the National Recovery Administration. Contained in the collection are the reports from the Executive Board meetings, the bound reports and resolutions from the yearly National Executive Board meetings, constitutions and by-laws, and financial statements. Other information and documents of the National Coat and Suit Industry Recovery Boards can be found in the related collection 6036/010.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5780: ILGWU records 5780/020: ILGWU. New York Cloak Joint Board records 6036/010: National Coat & Suit Industry Recovery Board records
Clothing workers -- Labor unions -- New York (State) -- New York.; International Ladies' Garment Workers' Union -- Archives.; Cloak, Suit and Skirt Manufacturers' Protective Association (New York, N.Y.)
5767601
- Minutes of the Executive Committee, The Cloak, Suit and Manufacturers' Protective Association, 1910-1914 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Bound volume
- Minutes of the Executive Committee, The Cloak, Suit and Manufacturers' Protective Association, 1915-1916 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Minutes of the Executive Committee, The Cloak, Suit and Manufacturers' Protective Association, 1917 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Local matters: City sales tax, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Local matters: Crime prevention program, 1971-1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Local matters: Insurance pilferage, 1963-1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Local matters: Mayor John Lindsay tax program, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Local matters: Mayor's office/Apparel, 1966-1976 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Local matters: New York unemployment insurance, 1959-1976 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Local matters: New York unemployment insurance, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Local matters: Occupancy tax, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Local matters: Joint Rent Action Committee, 1959-1962 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Local matters: Rent control, 1959-1970 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Local matters: Trucking strike, 1961 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Local matters: Waste disposal, 1968-1970 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Miscellaneous: Apparel Association of America, proposed new national organization, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Miscellaneous: Apparel Industries Inter-Association Committee correspondence, 1962-1975 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Miscellaneous: Apparel Industries Inter-Association Committee dues, 1965-1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Miscellaneous: Apparel Industries Inter-Association Committee members, 1962-1969 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Miscellaneous: Apparel Industries Inter-Association Committee proposed new organization, 1974-1975 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- National matters: "Care" labeling, Federal Trade Commission [Folder 1 of 2], 1967-1973 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- National matters: "Care" labeling, Federal Trade Commission [Folder 2 of 2], 1967-1973 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Exports (Box 2, Folder 20)
  No date
- National matters: Flammable fabrics, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- National matters: Freight Traffic Services (Richard Tobey, President), 1969-1976 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- National matters: Imports, chief weight, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- National matters: Imports [Folder 1 of 2], 1966-1975 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- National matters: Imports [Folder 2 of 2], 1966-1975 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- National matters: Interstate sales tax, 1961-1975 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- National matters: Wool imports, rule 26, 1953-1972 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- National matters: Wool imports, 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Trade practices: Dating, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 29)
- Trade practices: Pre-ticketing, 1962-1973 (Box 2, Folder 30)
- Trade practices: Trade provisions and regulations, 1955-1975 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- Spare notices, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Spare notices, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Spare notices, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Spare notices, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Spare notices, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 5a)
- Spare notices, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Spare notices, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 6a)
- Spare notices, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Spare notices, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Spare notices [Folder 1 of 3], 1962 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Spare notices [Folder 2 of 3], 1962 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Spare notices [Folder 3 of 3], 1962 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Spare notices, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Spare notices, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Spare notices, 1959 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Spare notices, 1958 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Spare notices, 1957 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Spare notices, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Spare notices, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Spare notices, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Spare notices, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Spare notices, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Spare notices, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Spare notices, 1950 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Spare notices, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Spare notices, 1948 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Spare notices, 1947 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- Spare notices, 1946 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- Spare notices, 1945 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Spare notices, 1942 (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Spare notices, 1941 (Box 3, Folder 29)
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1967 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  29th meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1966 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  28th meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1961 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  25th meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1960 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  24th meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1959 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  23rd meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1958 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  22nd meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1957 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  21st meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1956 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  20th meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1955 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  19th meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1954 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  18th meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1953 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  17th meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1952 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  16th meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1951 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  15th meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1950 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  14th meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1949 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  13th meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  12th meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, semi-annual meeting, 1947 (Box 4, Folder 17)
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1946 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  11th meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  9th meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1943 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  8th meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  7th meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, semi-annual meeting, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  6th meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1941 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, semi-annual meeting, 1940 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1939 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  4th meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, meeting of the Executive Board, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  3rd meeting
- National Board of the Coast and Suit Industry, semi-annual meeting (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Reports and Resolutions of Executive Board, 1958-1961 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Reports and Resolutions of Executive Board, 1954-1957 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Reports and Resolutions of Executive Board, 1950-1953 (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Coat and suit survey [Folder 1 of 3], 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Coat and suit survey [Folder 2 of 3], 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Coat and suit survey [Folder 3 of 3], 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Coat and suit survey binder (Box 5, Folder 16)
  Empty, contents of binder in folders 13 through 15.
- Coat and Suit Merchandising Study, Part 1: A Study of Store Buyers and Resident Buyers, 1963 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  Circa 1963
- Publications on women's garment industry, 1946-1971 (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Audits and surveys [Folder 1 of 3], 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 1)
- Audits and surveys [Folder 2 of 3], 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 2)
- Audits and surveys [Folder 3 of 3], 1963-4964 (Box 6, Folder 3)
- Award luncheon, contest, May 17, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 4)
- Bell and Stanton, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- Bell and Stanton, public relations committee, 1968-1970 (Box 6, Folder 6)
- By-laws and constitution, 1940-1964 (Box 6, Folder 7)
- By-laws, 1969-1971 (Box 6, Folder 8)
- Federal Trade Commission, Wool Products Labeling Act, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Coat and Suit Festival, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 10)
- Wilbur Daniels, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 11)
- Eastern Region Conference, June 1968 (Box 6, Folder 12)
- Federal Trade Commission Parley, Washington, October 17, 1962 re Advertising Allowances [Folder 2 of 2] (Box 6, Folder 13)
- Federal Trade Commission Parley, Washington, October 17, 1962 re Advertising Allowances [Folder 1 of 2] (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Federal Trade Commission and Rabiner & Jontow, Inc. (Erwin Feldman, attorney), 1965 (Box 6, Folder 15)
- Federal Trade Commission, fake furs, 1963-1964 (Box 6, Folder 16)
- Financial statements, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 17)
- Financial statements, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 18)
- Label sales, 1963-1971 (Box 6, Folder 19)
- Public relations [Folder 1 of 2], 1968 (Box 6, Folder 20)
- Public relations [Folder 2 of 2], 1968 (Box 6, Folder 21)
- Subcommittee on Traffic [Folder 1 of 2], 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 22)
- Subcommittee on Traffic [Folder 2 of 2], 1970-1972 (Box 6, Folder 23)
- Subcommittee on Traffic proposed reorganization, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 24)
- Manufacturer's Council (Canada), 1968 (Box 6, Folder 25)
- Representative John G. Dow, 1968-1969 (Box 6, Folder 26)
- Pacific Coast Regional meetings, 1966-1968 (Box 6, Folder 27)
- Los Angeles Coat and Suit Manufacturers, 1965-1971 (Box 6, Folder 28)
- Administrative committee, 1969-1970 (Box 6, Folder 29)
- Research Department statistics, 1964-1970 (Box 6, Folder 30)
- Coat and suit survey [Folder 1 of 2], 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 31)
- Coat and suit survey [Folder 2 of 2], 1964-1965 (Box 6, Folder 32)
- Correspondence, reports, 1974-1976 (Box 7, Folder 1)
- Correspondence, reports, 1972-1973 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  August 1972-December 1973
- Correspondence, reports, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  March 1972-July 1972
- Correspondence, reports, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  February 1972.
- Correspondence, reports, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Financial data, 1969-1972 (Box 7, Folder 6)
- Apparel industry, historical background, 1940-1949 (Box 8, Folder 1)
- Coat and suit, low end merchandise survey, 1938-1939 (Box 8, Folder 2)
- Independent Association of Women's Apparel Manufacturers v. ILGWU, 1952 (Box 8, Folder 3)
- Administration of designations under limitation, 1941 (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Apparel industry, section work, time studies, 1934-1953 (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Transcription of first hearing on coat and suit code authority, 1933 (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Codes, 1933-1955 (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Codes, surveys, background material, 1953-1972 (Box 8, Folder 8)